

Product Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Product Management, Requirement Gathering, Web Development, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Entity Framework, HTML, CSS, Javascript, .NET



Current Designation: Product Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Cognitive Platform Solutions Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Coimbatore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application Programming, Web Development, Entity Framework, HTML, CSS, Javascript, .NET, ADO. Net, .NET

Framework, ASP. Net, WCF, LINQ, SQL Server, MVVM, MVC, Angularjs, Node. Js, Bootstrap

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Software Professional with 4 years of experience in .NET Technologies

Experience in application development using C#, ADO.NET, Dot Net Core and Entity Framework as the Database data consumer.

Experience in design and development of applications using .NET Framework and Web technologies like Angular, CSS, Ajax, Razor View and HTML5.

Experience in SQL Server, developing T-SQL queries and stored procedures.

Experience in Javascript, JQuery.

Experience in WCF, Web API and Entity Framework with LINQ.

Work Experience

Cognitive Platform Solutions as Product Engineer Jun 2019 to Till Date

Working as a Dot Net Developer

Sutherland Global Services as Dot Net Developer

Sep 2016 to May 2019

Dot Net Developer

Sutherland Global Services as Specialist in Quality

Feb 2015 to Sep 2016

As a Specialist in Quality worked to categorise the customers feedback about the agents, service and products.

Sutherland Global Services as Consultant

Sep 2014 to Jan 2015

As a Seller Support Associate worked as the primary interface between Amazon and our 3rd party sellers, providing email support governed by internal service level agreements.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Sastra University in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C# .Net	
.NET Framework, Dot Net Core	
WCF, Web API, Entity Framework	
LINQ	
Microsoft SQL Server	
HTML5, CSS, XML, AJAX	
Javascript, JQuery, Razor View	
Visual Studio .Net, Visual Studio Code	
Angular	
Team Foundation Server, Tortoise SVN	
Lucene .Net	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Tamil	Expert			
Sourashtra	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Time & Attendance - Global Client: Sutherland Global Services

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 Project Location: Chennai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Other Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Dot Net Core 2.0, C#, Razor View, Web API, Entity Framework, LINQ, MS SQL Server, Angular7, CSS,

Javascript, jQuery, Ajax for effective UI. Role Description: Dot Net Developer

Project Details: Time and Attendance is a web application where everyday employees mark attendance, request, apply or

approve leave days.

Project Title: Time & Attendance - Kosovo Client: Sutherland Global Services

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2018 - Dec 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Location: Chennai

Role: Other Team Size: 5

Skill Used: MVC, Web API, C#, Razor View, Entity Framework, LINQ, MS SQL Server 2012, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax

for effective UI.

Created RDLC to generate reports.

Role Description: Dot Net Developer

Project Details: Time and Attendance is a web application where everyday employees mark attendance, request, apply or approve leave days. Generate reports and view attendance summary details.

Project Title: Service Quality Management System (SQMS)

Client: Sutherland Global Services Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2016 - Jun 2018

Project Location: Chennai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Other Team Size: 5

Skill Used: WCF, C#, MS SQL, HTML5, ADO.NET, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax for effective UI.

Role Description: Dot Net Developer

Project Details: SQMS is a web based Quality Management System to evaluate calls and employees performance. It helps to monitor employee performance, calibration details and evaluate call qualities. Generate reports and view summary details

based on programs.

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Category: General Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time